All right. So, um, in the last one, I
showed you how to sort them. Another
thing you might want to do with arrays,
um, is you might want to aggregate all
of the information inside of that. Or,
in other words, you may want to reduce
this entire array down to a single
value. So, the way that works is rather
than calling this dossort function,
you're going to call a dot um, reduce
function.
This function takes in a function and it
can optionally accept up to four
parameters. We're probably only going to
use two. So it will accept the previous
value and a current value. So if I call
Justice League.reduce on this, it needs
to accept a function. Okay. So we'll
write our function and um it should
accept the previous value. So we'll call
that previous and then we'll accept the
current value. And then it says, well,
how do you want to aggregate this
information? So if I was going through
this list and I wanted to sum up the
number of villains that were caught, I
would say take the previous value, add
on the current value, and make that. So
that would be 12 + 20, so be 32. And
then I would say, okay, now take that 32
and add on this 15. then add on this 18,
then add on this 10. So in other words,
what I'm doing is I'm taking the
previous value and I'm adding on the
current value. So what do I want to
return here? I want to return the
previous value plus the current value.
Well, let's save this and see what
happens. Oh dear, we have a mess here.
Well, what is each value in the Justice
League array? Each value in the Justice
League array is an array. So if we want
to um take the previous value and add on
the current value, well, we don't want
to add on an entire array to the
previous value. We want to add on
the third position of the current value.
So the third position of Bruce Wayne
Batman is 20. So let's save that and
we'll see what we've got. Well, we've
got Clark can't see Superman and then
this really long number which is all of
the numbers concatenated together.
Why did that happen? Well, here's a
caveat that you need to know about
reduce. Reduce always starts at the
first position
of the array. So, if we're looking at
Justice League, it takes the first
position of the array and puts that into
current. So current would be this array
of Bruce Wayne Batman 20. So that's
what's going in here. Previous is it
uses the first value in this array as
the previous value. So what is the
previous value here? Well, it's Clark K
Superman and it's the entire array. So
what we're doing is we're saying take
the entire array from the first position
concatenate on
20.
Then take all of that and put that into
the previous position. So we take all of
this plus 20 added to the end. And then
we do it again and again and again. If
you don't want it to start with the
first position in the array, then you
have to give it another piece of
information in this reduce. So we gave
it a function for how we want to reduce
all the information.
Um, but the next thing we need to do is
we put a comma and we need to give it an
initial value. So, we're saying let's
start with zero
villains and then we're going to take
the previous value plus the current
value and um so now the previous value
is going to start at zero. The current
value is going to be this array. So,
we're going to say the previous value 0
plus the current value of 12. Add those
together and you get 12. And then it
will continue on through this array. So
if we save this and we come over, we get
160.